Guide to the Eugene O'Neill Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Eugene O'Neill collection
1912-1993
YCAL MSS 124
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
12.03
(30 boxes) + 4 broadside folders and 1 art storage item
The Eugene O'Neill Collection consists of material by or pertaining to O'Neill, including correspondence, writings of O'Neill, writings of others, photographs, legal documents, clippings, and programs. Correspondents include O'Neill's lawyers, Harry Weinberger and Winfield E. Aronberg; a collector of his works, Keith H. Baker; his agent, Kenneth Macgowan; his and Carlotta's friends Dale Edward Fern, Armina Marshall, Dudley Nichols, Robert Sisk, Fania Marinoff Van Vechten, and Marion Welch; and Carlotta's daughter, Cynthia Chapman Stram, and her grandson, Gerald Eugene Stram. There are letters between O'Neill's biographers and others to Gaylord Farm Sanatorium regarding his stay there, and between biographer Louis Sheaffer and Hazel A. Johnson. There is also correspondence between Harry Weinberger and Agnes Boulton regarding her divorce settlement with O'Neill. Writings include drafts, proofs, programs, and clippings for some of O'Neill's plays, as well as works by others about O'Neill's life and writings. The photographs include prints of O'Neill and his family, among other subjects. There are also legal documents regarding his plays, and versions of Carlotta's wills.
O'Neill, Eugene, 1888-1953
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired by gift and purchase from various sources. Source information is recorded on the folders. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Restricted Fragile in boxes 24-26, and the sculpture of Eugene O'Neill, may only be consulted with permission of the appropriate curator. Preservation photocopies or photographic prints for reference use have been substituted in the main files.
EUGENE O'NEILL (1888-1953)
A biographical timeline is provided in the Eugene O'Neill Papers (YCAL MSS 123).
Scope and Contents
The Eugene O'Neill Collection consists of material by or pertaining to Eugene O'Neill, including correspondence, writings of Eugene O'Neill, writings of others, photographs, legal documents, clippings, and programs. The collection spans the years 1912 to 1993 (the bulk of the material is from 1921 to 1967), and is organized into five series: Correspondence, Writings, Photographs, Other Material, and 2011 Addition and are housed in 28 boxes.
Series I, Correspondence, is organized into four subseries: Eugene O'Neill Correspondence, Carlotta Monterey O'Neill Correspondence, Family Correspondence, and Third Party Correspondence. Each subseries is arranged alphabetically. Eugene O'Neill Correspondence contains letters between O'Neill and others. Because Carlotta Monterey O'Neill often wrote on his behalf, her letters from O'Neill's lifetime have been interfiled here as well. Correspondents include O'Neill's lawyers, Harry Weinberger and Winfield E. Aronberg; a collector of O'Neill's works, Keith H. Baker; O'Neill's agent, Kenneth Macgowan; and friends Dudley and Esta Nichols, Robert Sisk, and Marion Welch (a New London, Connecticut friend, to whom O'Neill wrote in 1905). The files for Armina Marshall (folders 48-54) and Fania Marinoff Van Vechten (folders 88-110) mainly contain letters from Carlotta. Carlotta Monterey O'Neill Correspondence dates from the years after O'Neill's death and chiefly concerns Carlotta's work on behalf of O'Neill's literary estate. Correspondents during this period include Dale Edward Fern, Dudley and Esta Nichols, Robert Sisk, and Fania Marinoff Van Vechten.
Family Correspondence contains letters from O'Neill to family members from 1922 to 1951, and letters from Carlotta to family members from 1951 to 1965. Recipients of O'Neill's letters include Carlotta; his first wife, Kathleen Pitt-Smith; and Carlotta's daughter from a previous marriage, Cynthia Chapman Stram. Recipients of Carlotta's letters include Cynthia Chapman Stram; Carlotta's grandson, Gerald Eugene Stram; and her son-in-law, Roy Stram.
Third Party Correspondence includes correspondence between Gaylord Farm Sanatorium and O'Neill biographers and others making inquiries about O'Neill's stay there. In addition, there are letters from Hazel A. Johnson to Louis Sheaffer regarding Sheaffer's biography of O'Neill ( O'Neill: Son and Playwright and O'Neill: Son and Artist ), and two small groups of correspondence with O'Neill's lawyers, Harry Weinberger (including letters from Agnes Boulton, Oona Chaplin, and Shane Rudraighe O'Neill) and Winfield E. Aronberg.
Additional correspondence can be found in Series V. 2011 Addition. There are photocopies of letters between Eugene and Carlotta O'Neill and Kenneth Macgowan, as well as four autograph manuscript letters, signed, from Carlotta to Macgowan.
Series II, Writings, is organized into three subseries: Plays, Other Writings, and Writings of Others. Each subseries is arranged alphabetically. Plays contains drafts, proofs, programs, and clippings; some of the drafts and proofs are corrected by O'Neill. Plays represented include The Ancient Mariner, The Fountain, The Iceman Cometh, Mourning Becomes Electra, and Strange Interlude. Other Writings contains a poem, "Ballad of the Birthday of the Most Gracious of Ladyes," dated 24 May 1913, and possibly addressed to Mary A. Clark (in addition, there are letters from O'Neill to Clark in Series I). Writings of Others contains writings about O'Neill's work and life by various authors, including Barrett Harper Clark, Walter Prichard Eaton, Egil Törnqvist, and Elisabeth Weiss. This subseries also contains Martin David Levy's drafts of the opera adaptation of Mourning Becomes Electra, and a photocopy of an article from A.M.A. Archives of Neurology that uses O'Neill's autopsy as a case study.
Series III, Photographs, is organized into two subseries: Loose Prints, and Scrapbooks. Some of the photographs are copy prints and have been so noted. In some cases, the original photograph may be in the Eugene O'Neill Papers (YCAL MSS 123). In other cases, the library does not own the original.
The first subseries, Loose Prints, is organized into Eugene O'Neill, and Other. The first group contains snapshots of O'Neill, circa 1893 to 1941; one studio portrait from the 1920s; four photographs of portraits of O'Neill (two drawings and one bust); a home movie made in Bermuda, probably in 1927; and two photographs taken in 1969 of O'Neill's grave in Boston. The second group, Other, contains photographs of O'Neill's second wife, Agnes Boulton, with his son, Shane; his daughter, Oona Chaplin; his third wife, Carlotta Monterey O'Neill; and his dog, Silverdene Emblem ("Blemie"). There are also photographs of Beacon Farm (taken in 1965) in Northport, New York (where the O'Neills lived in 1931); of Casa Genotta in Sea Island, Georgia (taken in 1932 and sent by Carlotta to Carl Van Vechten in 1936); of a Swedish production of Ile in 1958; and of a drawing that was probably used as an advertisement for the 1962 motion picture of Long Day's Journey Into Night.
Scrapbooks contains photographs taken in 1973 of prints in a scrapbook assembled by Marion Welch in June 1905; the photographs show O'Neill and Welch in New London. There is also a 1948 printed version of The Plays of Eugene O'Neill in which Carlotta pasted photographs of O'Neill taken between 1929 and 1931.
Series IV, Other Materials, is organized into two subseries: Legal Material, and Other. Legal Material contains agreements regarding productions of O'Neill's plays, 1923-1955; documents retaining Harry Weinberger as O'Neill's attorney; a document transferring O'Neill's rights in his plays to Carlotta Monterey O'Neill; and versions of O'Neill's wills, from 1947 to 1951. Other contains Carlotta's engagement calendar for 1958, clippings about O'Neill and his work, excerpts from Russel Crouse's diary for 1944-1953 regarding the O'Neills, material relating to the 1967 issue of the Eugene O'Neill stamp, a memorial brochure for M. Eleanor Fitzgerald, and a sculpture by N. W. Legassie based on a photograph of O'Neill as a boy. (A copy of the photograph is located in Series III, box 17, folder 279.)
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century; Dramatists, American -- 20th Century; Playwriting; Theater -- United States; Theater programs; Aronberg, Winfield E.; Baker, Keith H., 1906-1986; Boulton, Agnes, 1893-1968; Fern, Dale Edward; Johnson, Hazel A.; Macgowan, Kenneth, 1888-1963; Marshall, Armina; Nichols, Dudley, 1895-1960; O'Neill, Carlotta; O'Neill, Eugene, 1888-1953; Sheaffer, Louis; Sisk, Robert, 1903-1964; Stram, Cynthia Chapman; Stram, Gerald Eugene; Marinoff, Fania, 1890-1971; Weinberger, Harry, 1888-; Welch, Marion; Gaylord Farm Sanatorium
- Correspondence, 1912-1953; Series I; 3.8; (10 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Correspondence, is organized into four subseries: Eugene O'Neill Correspondence, Carlotta Monterey O'Neill Correspondence, Family Correspondence, and Third Party Correspondence. Each subseries is arranged alphabetically.
  - EUGENE O'NEILL CORRESPONDENCE
    - Aronberg, Winfield E., 1944-1951, undated (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
    - Baker, Keith H.
      - Correspondence, 1932-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, 1941 Jan-Aug (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, 1941 Sep-1942 Mar (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence, 1942 May-1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, 1948 Dec-1949 Mar (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence, 1949 Apr-Sep (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence, 1949 Nov-1951 Mar (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence, 1951 Apr-Sep (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence, 1951 Oct-1953 May (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Carey, Albert B., 1951, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Clark, Mary A., 1923-1926 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Crouse, Russel, 1934-1953 (Box 2, Folder 16-19)
    - Elser, Frank B., 1926-1932 (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
    - Fern, Dale Edward, 1947-1953 (Box 2, Folder 22-24)
    - Gaylord Farm Sanatorium
      - Correspondence (photocopy), 1912 Dec 20 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Correspondence, 1914-1950 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Griesser, Marjorie, 1921, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Guaranty Trust Company of New York, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Helburn, Theresa, 1921 Jan 31 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Hurn, Philip, 1927 May 31 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Krutch, Joseph Wood, 1927, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Langner, Lawrence, 1921 Feb 9 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Loving, Pierre, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Lyman, David Russell
      Related Archival Materials note
      See: Gaylord Farm Sanatorium, box 2, folders 25-26
    - McCartan, Patrick, 1934 Jun 11 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Macgowan, Kenneth
      - Correspondence, 1921-1923 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - Correspondence, 1924-1925 Mar (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - Correspondence, 1925 Apr-1926 Mar (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - Correspondence, 1926 Apr-Aug (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - Correspondence, 1926 Sep-1927 Jul (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - Correspondence, 1927 Aug-1928 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - Correspondence, 1929-1930 May (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - Correspondence, 1930 Jun (Box 3, Folder 42)
        Encloses photographs at Château du Plessis (St. Antoine-du-Rocher, Indre et Loire, France): three of EO in Bugatti racing car; EO wearing striped robe, standing next to pool; EO wearing bathing suit, standing on pool deck; two views of pool; Blemie lying in driveway; Blemie lying on lawn; Ben lying on lawn; nine views of house and grounds.
      - Correspondence, 1931-1934 (Box 3, Folder 43)
      - Correspondence, 1936-1937 Jan (Box 3, Folder 44)
      - Correspondence, 1937 Feb-1938 (Box 3, Folder 45)
      - Correspondence, 1939-1950, undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Manning, Doris, 1949-1950, undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Marshall, Armina
      - Correspondence, 1931-1940 (Box 3, Folder 48)
      - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 49)
        Letter dated 1941 Oct 17 encloses three photographs of Oona Chaplin at Tao House (Danville, Calif.), 1941 Aug: swimming in pool; wearing bathing suit, standing in garden; sitting at table outside (all with EO cut out of picture).
      - Correspondence, 1942-1944 (Box 3, Folder 50)
      - Correspondence, 1945-1948 Mar (Box 3, Folder 51)
      - Correspondence, 1948 Apr-Dec (Box 3, Folder 52)
      - Correspondence, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 53)
      - Correspondence, undated (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Mary Leo, Sister, 1925-1931 (Box 3, Folder 55)
      Letter dated 1929 Mar 26 encloses three photographs of EO in Cap-d'Ail (France), 1929 Feb, inscribed by EO: wearing checkered sweater on porch, leaning against building, front view; wearing checkered sweater on porch, leaning against building, side view; sitting wearing checkered sweater, reading newspaper inside French doors.
    - Mayfield, Earle Bradford, 1924 Aug 25 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Mayfield, John S., 1924-1928 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Mickle, Alan Durward, 1927-1929 (Box 3, Folder 58)
      With clipping of review of Mickle's Studies on Six Plays of Eugene O'Neill.
    - Moise, Nina, 1918-1923 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Museum of the City of New York, 1933-1951 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Nichols, Dudley Nichols, Esta
      - Correspondence, 1932-1940 Apr (Box 4, Folder 61)
      - Correspondence, 1940 May-Oct (Box 4, Folder 62)
      - Correspondence, 1940 Nov-Dec (Box 4, Folder 63)
      - Correspondence, 1941-1946 (Box 4, Folder 64)
      - Correspondence, 1947 Jan-Jun (Box 4, Folder 65)
      - Correspondence, 1947 Aug-1948 (Box 4, Folder 66)
      - Correspondence, 1949-1952 (Box 4, Folder 67)
      - Correspondence, 1953, undated (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Patterson, Robert Lee, Jr., 1948-1951 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1942 Apr 11 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Quinn, Emily, 1921 Apr 1 (Box 4, Folder 71)
      i.e., Mrs. Edmond T. Quinn (later Mrs. Shepherd Stevens).
    - Roberts, Irene Roberts, John, 1945-1953, undated (Box 4, Folder 72-74)
      Includes one clipping regarding EO, Jr.
    - Seymour, May Davenport
      See: Museum of the City of New York, box 3, folder 60
    - Sisk, Robert
      - Correspondence, 1928-1930 Jul (Box 5, Folder 75)
      - Correspondence, 1930 Aug-Dec (Box 5, Folder 76)
      - Correspondence, 1931-1933 Jun (Box 5, Folder 77)
      - Correspondence, 1933 Jul-1935 (Box 5, Folder 78)
      - Correspondence, 1936-1939 (Box 5, Folder 79)
      - Correspondence, 1940-1942 (Box 5, Folder 80)
      - Correspondence, 1943-1947 (Box 5, Folder 81)
      - Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 82)
      - Correspondence, undated (Box 5, Folder 83)
    - Thorburn, Mr., [1926 Mar?] (Box 5, Folder 84)
    - Van Vechten, Carl
      - Correspondence, 1929, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 85)
      - Correspondence, 1936, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 86)
      - Correspondence, 1946 Jun 16 (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - Van Vechten, Fania Marinoff
      See also: Carl Van Vechten, box 5, folder 86
      - Correspondence, 1923-1928 (Box 5, Folder 88)
      - Correspondence, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 89)
      - Correspondence, 1930-1933 Mar (Box 5, Folder 90)
      - Correspondence, 1933 May (Box 5, Folder 91)
      - Correspondence, 1933 Jun-1934 Feb (Box 6, Folder 92)
      - Correspondence, 1934 Apr-1935 May (Box 6, Folder 93)
      - Correspondence, 1935 Jun-Oct (Box 6, Folder 94)
      - Correspondence, 1935 Nov-Dec (Box 6, Folder 95)
      - Correspondence, 1936 Jan-Jul (Box 6, Folder 96)
      - Correspondence, 1936 Aug-Sep (Box 6, Folder 97)
      - Correspondence, 1936 Oct-1937 Jan (Box 6, Folder 98)
      - Correspondence, 1937 Mar-May (Box 6, Folder 99)
      - Correspondence, 1937 Jul-Aug (Box 6, Folder 100)
      - Correspondence, 1937 Sep-Dec (Box 6, Folder 101)
      - Correspondence, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 102)
      - Correspondence, 1939 Jan-Feb (Box 6, Folder 103)
      - Correspondence, 1939 Apr-Dec (Box 6, Folder 104)
      - Correspondence, 1940 Jan-Oct (Box 6, Folder 105)
      - Correspondence, 1940 Nov-1941 Feb (Box 7, Folder 106)
      - Correspondence, 1941 May-1942 Aug (Box 7, Folder 107)
      - Correspondence, 1942 Sep-1944 Apr (Box 7, Folder 108)
      - Correspondence, 1944 Sep-1947 May (Box 7, Folder 109)
      - Correspondence, 1947 Jul-1949 (Box 7, Folder 110)
    - Weinberger, Harry
      - Correspondence, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 111)
      - Correspondence, 1940 Jan-Sep (Box 7, Folder 112)
      - Correspondence, 1940 Oct-1941 Jul (Box 7, Folder 113)
      - Correspondence, 1941 Aug-Dec (Box 7, Folder 114)
      - Correspondence, 1942 Jan-May (Box 7, Folder 115)
      - Correspondence, 1942 Jun-Sep (Box 7, Folder 116)
      - Correspondence, 1942 Oct-Dec (Box 7, Folder 117)
      - Correspondence, 1943 Jan-Feb (Box 7, Folder 118)
      - Correspondence, 1943 Mar-May (Box 7, Folder 119)
      - Correspondence, 1943 Jun-1944 Jan (Box 7, Folder 120)
    - Weiss, Elisabeth, 1934 May 12 (Box 7, Folder 121)
      With typescript copy of EO's letter to Weiss, 1930 Apr 2.
    - Welch, Marion, 1905 (Box 7, Folder 122-123)
  - CARLOTTA MONTEREY O'NEILL CORRESPONDENCE
    - Baker, Keith H., 1953-1956 (Box 8, Folder 124)
    - Cadwalader, Wickersham & Taft, 1955-1964 (Box 8, Folder 125)
    - Crouse, Russel Crouse, Anna, 1953-1957 (Box 8, Folder 126)
    - Fern, Dale Edward, 1953-1959 (Box 8, Folder 127-129)
    - Lake, Katherine, undated (Box 8, Folder 130)
    - Marshall, Armina, [1953] (Box 8, Folder 131)
    - Museum of the City of New York, 1958, undated (Box 8, Folder 132)
    - Nichols, Dudley Nichols, Esta, 1953-1959 (Box 8, Folder 133-135)
    - Quintero, José, 1958 Sep 7
      See: Series IV, Other Material, Engagement calendar, box 21, folder 324
    - Roberts, Irene Roberts, John, 1953-1962, undated (Box 8, Folder 136-137)
      Includes one clipping regarding Oona Chaplin.
    - Rubin, Jane, 1958 Dec (Box 8, Folder 138)
    - Seymour, May Davenport
      See: Museum of the City of New York, box 8, folder 132
    - Shyre, Paul, 1961 May 6 (Box 8, Folder 139)
    - Sisk, Robert, 1953-1958, undated (Box 8, Folder 140-141)
    - Van Vechten, Fania Marinoff
      - Correspondence, [1953 Nov] (Box 8, Folder 142)
      - Correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box 8, Folder 143)
      - Correspondence, 1955 Oct 31 (Box 8, Folder 144)
      - Correspondence, 1956 Jan 8 (Box 8, Folder 145)
      - Correspondence, 1959, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 146)
  - FAMILY CORRESPONDENCE
    - Carlotta Monterey O'Neill
      - To Cynthia Chapman Stram, 1951-1965 (Box 9, Folder 147-149)
      - To Gerald Eugene Stram, 1953-1959 (Box 9, Folder 150)
      - To Roy Stram, 1951-1961 (Box 9, Folder 151)
        See also: Cynthia Chapman Stram, box 9, folders 148-149
    - Eugene O'Neill
      - To Carlotta Monterey O'Neill, [1926 Dec] (Box 9, Folder 152)
      - To Kathleen Pitt-Smith, 1922, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 153)
      - To Cynthia Chapman Stram, 1931-1951, undated (Box 9, Folder 154-156)
        Includes photograph (copy) of O'Neill sitting on rock writing in notebook (circa 1893-1894), inscribed by him, 1935 May 11.
  - THIRD PARTY CORRESPONDENCE
    - American Play Company to Arvid Paulson, 1924 Nov 28 (Box 10, Folder 157)
    - Aronberg, Winfield E.
      - To Lawrence Langner, 1951 Apr 9 (Box 10, Folder 158)
      - To Merrill Moore, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 159)
    - Boni & Liveright to B. Franklin, 1928 Mar 16 (Box 10, Folder 160)
      Encloses brochure for "The Works of Eugene O'Neill in Eight Volumes."
    - Bowen, Croswell to Cadwalader, Wickersham & Taft, undated (Box 10, Folder 161)
    - Burns & MacEachern to Yale University Press, 1956 Feb 21 (Box 10, Folder 162)
    - Charles Scribner's Sons to unidentified, undated (Box 10, Folder 163)
      Encloses brochures for The Complete Plays of Eugene O'Neill.
    - Commins, Saxe to Keith H. Baker, 1942 Mar 23 (Box 10, Folder 164)
    - Crawford, Jack, [19]09 Sep 18 (Box 10, Folder 165)
      Note regarding James O'Neill, who helped Crawford raise money for the orphans of John B. Hood. Above Crawford's note is signature of James O'Neill.
    - Gaylord Farm Sanatorium
      - From Doris Alexander, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 166)
      - From Jacob M. Berkowitz, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 167)
      - From The Connecticut State Medical Journal, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 168)
      - From The Fluoroscope, 1934 (Box 10, Folder 169)
      - From Arthur Gelb, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 170)
      - From Percy Hammond, 1921 (Box 10, Folder 171)
      - From James Alexander Miller (photocopy), 1912 Dec 17 (Box 10, Folder 172)
      - To James Alexander Miller, 1912 Dec 18 (Box 10, Folder 173)
      - From James Alexander Miller (photocopy), 1912 Dec 20 (Box 10, Folder 174)
      - To and from Lewis Jefferson Moorman (photocopies), 1953 (Box 10, Folder 175)
        With photocopy of Gaylord Farm Sanatorium medical record for EO and photocopies of two photographs of EO at Gaylord.
      - From and to National Association for the Study and Prevention of Tuberculosis (U.S.) (photocopies), 1913 (Box 10, Folder 176)
      - From and to James O'Neill, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 177)
      - From Shane Rudraighe O'Neill and Croswell Bowen, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 178)
      - From Louis Sheaffer, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 179)
      - From Herbert J. Stoeckel, 1950-1954 (Box 10, Folder 180)
      - From Joanne Wilson, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 181)
      - From Mamie, 1951 Jul 16 (Box 10, Folder 182)
    - Nichols, Dudley to Dale Edward Fern, 1949 May 13 (Box 10, Folder 183)
    - Sheaffer, Louis to Hazel A. Johnson, 1957-1973 (Box 10, Folder 184-186)
    - Weinberger, Harry
      - From Agnes Boulton, 1930-1943 (Box 10, Folder 187-188)
        Includes carbons from Weinberger.
      - From Oona Chaplin, [1941 Sep] (Box 10, Folder 189)
      - From Shane Rudraighe O'Neill, [1940?] (Box 10, Folder 190)
      - To John H. G. Pell, 1942-1944 (Box 10, Folder 191-192)
        Also includes Pell's letters to Weinberger.
      - To United States. Internal Revenue Service, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 193)
- Writings, 1913-1979; Series II; 2.2; (6 boxes)
  Series II, Writings, is organized into three subseries: Plays, Other Writings, and Writings of Others. Each subseries is arranged alphabetically.
  - PLAYS
    - Ah, Wilderness!. Programs and clipping, 1933-1969 (Box 11, Folder 194-195)
    - The Ancient Mariner
      - Draft, holograph, corrected, in The Rime of the Ancient Mariner and Christabel by Samuel Taylor Coleridge (New York and London: G.P. Putnam's Sons), undated (Box 11, Folder 196)
      - Program, 1929-1930 (Box 11, Folder 197)
    - Anna Christie. Programs and clipping, 1921-1969 (Box 11, Folder 198)
    - Cycle plays. More Stately Mansions
      - Programs, 1967-1970 (Box 11, Folder 199)
      - Clippings of reviews, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 200)
        Stored also in: Oversize, bsd, folder 350
    - Cycle plays. A Touch of the Poet. Brochure and clipping, 1963, undated (Box 11, Folder 201)
    - Days Without End. Programs, 1933, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 202)
    - Desire Under the Elms. Motion picture treatment, typescript carbon, [circa 1927] (Box 11, Folder 203)
    - Empty folder (Box 11, Folder 204)
    - Diff'rent
      - Draft, typescript carbon and holograph, in notebook, undated
        With letter from Gertrude Longval to [Joseph A.] Dermont, 1991 Apr 1.
      - Program, [1924-1925] (Box 11, Folder 205)
    - Dynamo
      - Early galley proof, n.y. Feb 25-27 (Box 11, Folder 206-207)
        Annotated in unidentified hand.
      - Programs, 1929 (Box 11, Folder 208)
    - The Emperor Jones. Programs, 1931, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 209)
    - The Fountain. Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, in volume, [circa 1925] (Box 11, Folder 210)